petcircle.com.au 2017-03-26

# Security & Privacy | Pet Circle

#### Privacy Statement

Pet Circle Pty Ltd (Pet Circle) maintains a thorough commitment to your privacy and protecting your personal information. Our privacy policy outlines our approach to privacy and how we collect, use and protect your personal information. It also sets out your rights in relation to accessing the personal information we collect and hold about you. We are bound by the Australian Privacy Principles (or APP's) in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth).

Our website may contain links to third party websites. As we are not responsible for how these third party websites collect, use and store your information, we recommend you review their privacy policy prior to accessing and/or using their website.

#### How we collect your personal information

Pet Circle collects personal information to purposefully conduct our business and services as an e-commerce organisation. Any personal information we collect, is done so when you perform a transaction on our website, register, subscribe to our newsletter or contact us.

**Pet Circle does _not_ store credit card numbers. These are securely held by a large third-party payment processor (eWay).** Personal information we do collect includes your name, address, email, phone number and billing address. All personal information that we collect will be done so in a lawful and unobtrusive manner.

When we collect information, attempts will be made to ensure each individual understands why such information is being collected, how it will be used and who such information will be given to.

#### Using the Pet Circle website

Upon visiting our website, cookies may be placed on your browser to allow you to login to your account, maintain a shopping cart and to purchase items in your shopping cart. Pet Circle may use this information to provide you with a better user experience and more relevant advertising and marketing messages.

By using the website and agreeing to this policy, you grant us permission to place and store cookies on your browser. Cookies collect limited information regarding your browser type, IP address, web pages visited and web page statistics. We may also use these cookies to collect demographics and interest data. We do not collect or use any information during this process that could identify you as an individual. The information is anonymous and is used to support customised digital advertising and reporting. Additionally, third parties we have contracted to provide services on our website (such as PayPal) may place and read cookies on your browser.

#### How we use your personal information

All personal information we collect, use and disclose, will only be done so to fulfil the purpose for which it was collected. Our use and disclosure of your personal information is for the purpose of enabling us to both carry out our function as an e-commerce business and provide you with a better user experience.

Where we do collect your personal information and disclose it to a third party, we ensure that it is done so in a protected manner.

#### Consent to use your personal information

Personal information will only be used for marketing purposes if you have given either express or implied consent. Implied consent is assumed when signing up to use our site, registering your email address, or participating in any promotions which require you to disclose your email address.

When registering or purchasing from Pet Circle, you consent to Pet Circle using your personal information, such as your email address, to provide you with offers and information regarding our products and services. All digital communications will comply with the requirements of the Spam Act 2003 (Cth).

#### Disclosure to third parties

Occasionally we do provide your personal information to third parties that are contracted to provide services. As some service providers are not located within Australia, cross-border transfer of such information will be done so in accordance with Australian Privacy Principle 8 (APP 8).

#### Security of your personal information

When using, collecting and storing your personal information, we take every step to ensure that this is done so in a secure manner. All reasonable steps are taken to ensure that your personal information is not accessed, disclosed or collected by any unauthorised persons or third parties.

#### Your rights to accessing your stored information and grievance procedures

Under The Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), you have certain rights to access the personal information we collect, or seek correction of the information we collect by contacting a customer service representative either at sales@petcircle.com.au or by phoning us on 1300 60 80 03.

We take all reasonable care to ensure that the personal information that we collect, use and disclose is accurate, up to date and complete.

Privacy Policy last updated 04/09/2015
